<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Domingo Club</title><link>https://domingoclub.com</link><description>Fermented food &amp; open-source tools</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 13:38:43 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Incubator Necklace</title><link>https://domingoclub.com/incubator-necklace.html</link><description>&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wear this necklace for 3 weeks and incubate edible mushrooms with the heat of your body. If you take well care of your micro pet, you may harvest some!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="body-incub01.JPG"/&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="body-incub03.JPG"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This incubator necklace is a playful invitation to observe and understand the collaboration with natural processes. The glass petri dish contains fungus spores and those spores need constant humidity and temperature to develop. So if you wear the necklace for 3 weeks in a row, the roots of the mushrooms will grow and when the necklace has turned white, mini edible mushrooms will grow in the bright spot where you will have left the necklace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="fabrication"&gt;Fabrication&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="body-incub07.JPG"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this prototype version, we 3D printed a Galaxy Black PLA holder for the 60x12mm glass petri dish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The source file is available on &lt;a href="https://github.com/domingoclub/incubator-necklace"&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="body-incub08.JPG"/&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="body-incub04.JPG"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, we inoculated mushroom spawn/mycelium into fresh coffee grounds and sealed the petri dish with a strip of paraffin film.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="instructions"&gt;Instructions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wear the necklace against your skin, under your t-shirt.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When the necklace is not being worn, it is recommended to store it in a dark place with a room temperature between 20°C and 27°C.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When the roots of the mushroom have fully developed and the content of glass petri dish has turned white (within 20-30 days), you can take the glass petri dish out of the necklace, remove the strip of paraffin film from around it and place the petri dish in a bright place out of direct sunlight. The petri dish should remain ...</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate></item><item><title>Bingo Escabelle</title><link>https://domingoclub.com/2021-07-11.html</link><description>&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;We sent a prototype version of our Incubator Necklace to &lt;a href="https://www.see-u.brussels/"&gt;See U Brussels&lt;/a&gt; in the context of their &lt;em&gt;Bingo Escabelle&lt;/em&gt; which took place on Sunday 11th July.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="admonition notes"&gt;
&lt;p class="admonition-title"&gt;What is an Incubator Necklace?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our incubator necklace is a playful invitation to observe and understand the collaboration with natural processes. Visit the &lt;a class="internal" href="incubator-necklace.html"&gt;incubator-necklace&lt;/a&gt; page to discover it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bingo Escabelle&lt;/em&gt; put the spotlight on engaged Brussels projects and collectives by presenting their creative work during a fun and convivial moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are looking forward to finding out who won this prize and became the new owner of this micro pet! Send us pictures 👀&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="body-incub01.JPG"/&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="body-incub03.JPG"/&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="body-incub-packed.JPG"/&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="bingo-escabelle.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;...</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate></item><item><title>Distributed Design and Decentralized Fabrication</title><link>https://domingoclub.com/distributed-design.html</link><description>&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the kitchen, it seems natural to share a good recipe and tips and tricks on how to please our taste buds. We share knowledge from one generation to the next. We preserve the cultural heritage while allowing it to be augmented by the findings of the community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sharing, collaboration, cooperation and re-appropriation are keys to the success of our project in order to move towards a sustainable society where we understand what we eat, what we do, what we use in our daily lives, a society where we observe and question what we usually take for granted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We therefore use the principles of distributed design and decentralized manufacturing for the tools we make. Which means that you can download our models, review and adapt them, and produce them yourself.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;...</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate></item><item><title>Distributed Design 2021</title><link>https://domingoclub.com/2021-07-01.html</link><description>&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;Good news! We won the Distributed Design Award 2021!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our project was first selected, among the 12 finalists, in the &lt;em&gt;Adaptable and open-design&lt;/em&gt; category and now, after a few weeks of suspense, we have just learned that we won the award for excellence! Woop woop!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll receive 2000€ to finance the development of the Domingo Club and our incubator. Long live the Domingo Club!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks distributeddesign!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="dd-prize.png"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;...</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate></item><item><title>New electronics on the way</title><link>https://domingoclub.com/2021-06-30.html</link><description>&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;New electronic system for the incubator being prototyped, soon with a Raspberry Pico and an OLED screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="antoineisprototyping.jpg"/&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="newscreen.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;...</description><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate></item><item><title>Food System Game Changer</title><link>https://domingoclub.com/2021-06-29.html</link><description>&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;EAT, IDEO, Thought For Food, The Rockefeller Foundation and Forum For the Future have joined forces to discover and support ideas, enterprises and initiatives that have the potential to transform our world’s food systems. The Food Systems Game Changers Lab is in support of the UN Food Systems Summit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the Domingo Club, we’re working with other game changers who have ideas, initiatives, and innovations that can bring positive change to global food systems—and the passion, grit, collaborative spirit, and determination required to take our solutions forward in partnership with others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're part of the innovating protein cohort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="gamechangerlab.png"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://thoughtforfood.org/"&gt;Thought For Food&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.rockefellerfoundation.org/"&gt;The Rockefeller Foundation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.openideo.com/"&gt;IDEO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://eatforum.org/"&gt;EAT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.forumforthefuture.org/"&gt;Forum For the Future&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.un.org/en/food-systems-summit"&gt;UN Food Systems Summit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;...</description><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate></item><item><title>The new version of the incubator is coming</title><link>https://domingoclub.com/2021-06-22.html</link><description>&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;We have started the design of the new version of our incubator, taking into account the feedback received since our previous prototype. In particular, its size!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone has different needs, tastes, space, and so does our incubator. We design our new model/prototype in a free and open-source software, &lt;a href="https://www.freecadweb.org/"&gt;Freecad&lt;/a&gt;, that offers everyone the possibility to use and modify our designs to meet their needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will be fabricating the new incubator this summer at &lt;a href="https://fablabbcn.org/"&gt;Fab Lab Barcelona&lt;/a&gt; as part of &lt;a href="https://foodshift2030.eu/"&gt;Food Shift&lt;/a&gt;'s Food Tech 3.0 programme. All the sources of our project will be available as soon as they are usable, on our website and most probably on &lt;a href="https://wikifactory.com/"&gt;Wikifactory&lt;/a&gt; ;-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="embed-container" style=""&gt;&lt;iframe allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" mozallowfullscreen="" src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/566284652" webkitallowfullscreen=""&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="admonition note"&gt;
&lt;p class="admonition-title"&gt;In the video&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A demo of our parametric model that can take "almost" any size. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;...</description><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate></item><item><title>Unstructured technical notes</title><link>https://domingoclub.com/unstructured-technical-notes.html</link><description>&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;h1 id="raspberry-pico"&gt;Raspberry Pico&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id="documentation"&gt;Documentation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/documentation/rp2040/getting-started/"&gt;Pico documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://datasheets.raspberrypi.org/pico/raspberry-pi-pico-python-sdk.pdf"&gt;Pico MicroPython documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://datasheets.raspberrypi.org/pico/Pico-R3-A4-Pinout.pdf"&gt;Pinout&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="installation"&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/documentation/rp2040/getting-started/#getting-started-with-micropython"&gt;Install MicroPython&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install rshell &lt;code&gt;pip3 install rshell&lt;/code&gt; (&lt;a href="https://www.twilio.com/blog/programming-raspberry-pi-pico-microcontroller-micropython"&gt;guide&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install &lt;a href="https://salsa.debian.org/minicom-team/minicom"&gt;Minicom&lt;/a&gt; (USB serial) - &lt;a href="https://aur.archlinux.org/packages/minicom-git/"&gt;AUR&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id="use"&gt;Use&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to the folder of your choice &lt;code&gt;cd pico/experiments/&lt;/code&gt; and create a &lt;code&gt;main.py&lt;/code&gt; file that will contain your MicroPython script&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;rshell -p /dev/ttyACM0 --buffer-size 512&lt;/code&gt; where &lt;code&gt;ttyACM0&lt;/code&gt; in the Pico adress on your machine. Run &lt;code&gt;dmesg -w&lt;/code&gt; to see the devices connected to your computer, and therefore the address of your Pico.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copy your local script to the pico by running &lt;code&gt;cp main.py /pyboard/main.py&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Close the rshell connection &lt;code&gt;CTRL + x&lt;/code&gt; and unplug/plug your Pico&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;minicom -b 115200 -o -D /dev/ttyACM0&lt;/code&gt; to read the serial communiction (replace &lt;code&gt;ttyACM0&lt;/code&gt; with your Pico address previously obtained)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h1 id="oled-screen-to-raspberry-pico-through-spi"&gt;OLED sc...</description><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate></item><item><title>Design in Age of Crisis</title><link>https://domingoclub.com/2021-06-07.html</link><description>&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;For those who are or will be in London this month (June 2021): You will be able to see the Domingo Club as part of the &lt;em&gt;Cathedral of Creativity&lt;/em&gt; taking place in the Somerset House galleries for the &lt;em&gt;Design in Age of Crisis exhibition&lt;/em&gt; - presented as part of the &lt;a href="https://www.londondesignbiennale.com/"&gt;London Design Biennale&lt;/a&gt;. Please take pictures if you go :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Forest for Change, London Design Biennale, Somerset House (Ed Reeve)" src="GlobalGoals_ed-reeve.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;...</description><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate></item><item><title>From One to Many</title><link>https://domingoclub.com/2021-06-02.html</link><description>&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last month we participated in &lt;a href="https://wikifactory.com/"&gt;WikiFactory&lt;/a&gt;'s #FromOneToMany challenge and they just announced that we won the functionality prize with our &lt;a class="internal" href="tempeh-moulds.html"&gt;tempeh-moulds&lt;/a&gt;, woop woop!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="compilation.png"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have won a form box machine that will help us to develop our mould series and research new materials by further exploring moulding and casting techniques.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="small:wikichallenge-01.jpg"/&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="small:wikichallenge-02.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Announcement video &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CPlTAAhqMBA/"&gt;→ link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Winners &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CPnMfI9I3kk/"&gt;→ link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;...</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate></item><item><title>3D printed moulds</title><link>https://domingoclub.com/3D-printed-moulds.html</link><description>&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Domingo Club 3D printed mould with tempeh preparation before incubation" src="tempeh-mould-rect-00.jpg"/&gt;
&lt;img alt="Ready to incubate!" src="tempeh-mould-rect-01.jpg"/&gt;
&lt;img alt="Fresh tempeh out of a Domingo Club 3D printed mould" src="tempeh-mould-rect-02.jpg"/&gt;
&lt;img alt="Ready to cook!" src="tempeh-mould-rect-07.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="the-design"&gt;The Design&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The design is pretty simple, but smooth and balanced. It consists of a ~120x80x30 mm container (3mm of thickness) with a lid. There are small perforations all around the container and on the lid to allow the tempeh to breath during the fermentation process. The lid has notches to hold two rubber bands to keep the soybeans compacted inside. And the bottom part of container has a removable coin to easily remove the tempeh from the mould after incubation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With these constraints put together, several forms can follow. We have for now, a rectangle, a zigzag and a stackable round mould.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Domingo Club tempeh mould in FreeCAD" src="compilation.png"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We use &lt;a href="https://www.freecadweb.org/"&gt;FreeCAD&lt;/a&gt;, an open-source parametric 3D modeler that you can download for free, to design our mould. Parametric modeling allows you to easily modify our design by going back into our spreadsheet and change the values in milimeters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="the-fabrication"&gt;The Fabrication&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Domingo Club 3D printed tempeh moulds" src="composition.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our moulds are 3D printed with our &lt;a href="https://www.prusa3d.com/original-prusa-mini/"&gt;Prusa Mini&lt;/a&gt; with PETG filament from &lt;a href="https://shop.prusa3d.com/fr/prusament/1300-prusament-petg-pistachio-green-1kg.html"&gt;Prusament&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We use PETG filament because the material is food grade but we realised ...</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate></item><item><title>Sriracha sauce in the making</title><link>https://domingoclub.com/2021-05-30.html</link><description>&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;This morning I came back from the local fruit and vegetable shop with a ton of chillies, with the idea of making a new sriracha sauce (a fermented chilli sauce from Thailand). This sauce never lasts long in our house, we eat it with just about everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="IMG_7729.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="admonition note"&gt;
&lt;p class="admonition-title"&gt;The recipe is coming&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll write our recipe as soon as we finish this batch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The recipe is composed of two steps with a fermentation time in between, which makes it quite quick and easy to make for an excellent and very spicy result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- [🔥 Sriracha sauce recipe 🔥](button:sriracha.html) --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Toni&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;...</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate></item><item><title>Why do we need moulds to make tempeh?</title><link>https://domingoclub.com/intro.html</link><description>&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;Traditional tempeh is often produced in Indonesia using Hibiscus leaves (for tempeh starter production) or Banana leaves (for tempeh production). In our western countries, sealed polyethylene pouch (=freezer bags) are more often used. Indeed, an appropriate packaging is important as it provides optimum oxygen supply, right level of humidity and temperature for inoculation and fermentation to occur during processing. But we want to implement a reusable method to produce tempeh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Image from Wikipedia: Traditional fresh tempeh at the market in Jakarta (Indonesia) wrapped in banana leaves" src="traditional-tempeh.jpg"/&gt;
&lt;img alt="Image from the Miso, Tempeh, Natto &amp;amp; Other Tasty Ferments book: Tempeh in a sealed polyethylene bag" src="zipbag-tempeh.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;...</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 May 2021 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate></item><item><title>The very first post</title><link>https://domingoclub.com/2021-05-29.html</link><description>&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to our new section: The Domingo Journal. Here we want to explain a little more deeply and naturally the things we do, that happen to us, that we create on a daily basis. To take you with us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because we don't want to centralise our content on platforms we don't trust, we decided to keep the scoop here and then relay it to our &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/domingoclub/"&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://sunbeam.city/@domingoclub"&gt;Mastodon&lt;/a&gt; (think of the free and open source version of Twitter) accounts and simply and brilliantly through our &lt;a href="https://domingoclub.com/rss.xml"&gt;RSS feed&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See you soon ☼&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;...</description><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate></item><item><title>Join the club</title><link>https://domingoclub.com/join.html</link><description>&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;div class="embed-container"&gt;&lt;iframe allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" mozallowfullscreen="" src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/547673474" webkitallowfullscreen=""&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are in the process of defining our project, sharpening our tools and developing a calendar of activities so that we can invite you all to explore fermentation together very soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are also thinking about the structure of the club, what form it should take, how to welcome members, what our common goals should be? Subscribe to our newsletter to be informed and involved in this process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script&gt;
  (function (s, e, n, d, er) {
    s['Sender'] = er;
    s[er] = s[er] || function () {
      (s[er].q = s[er].q || []).push(arguments)
    }, s[er].l = 1 * new Date();
    var a = e.createElement(n),
        m = e.getElementsByTagName(n)[0];
    a.async = 1;
    a.src = d;
    m.parentNode.insertBefore(a, m)
  })(window, document, 'script', 'https://cdn.sender.net/accounts_resources/universal.js', 'sender');
  sender('a947da335f7959')
&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;div class="sender-form-field" data-sender-form-id="kmf543xgaqn7qbtckzw"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We respect your privacy and will never share your email address with third parties. Never ever.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;...</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate></item><item><title>Toolbox</title><link>https://domingoclub.com/toolbox.html</link><description>&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;We are currently working on it! Content coming soon.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;...</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate></item><item><title>Lasercut shelves</title><link>https://domingoclub.com/lasercut-shelves.html</link><description>&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;We are currently working on it! Content coming soon.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;...</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate></item><item><title>Food Grade</title><link>https://domingoclub.com/food-grade.html</link><description>&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;We are currently working on it! Content coming soon.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;...</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate></item><item><title>Electronics</title><link>https://domingoclub.com/electronics.html</link><description>&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;We are currently working on a more complete documentation which will then allow us to focus on version 0.3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pending a new transcription, the documentation is available on &lt;a href="https://antoine.studio/incubator-v0-2.html"&gt;antoine.studio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;...</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate></item><item><title>cabinet</title><link>https://domingoclub.com/cabinet.html</link><description>&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;We are currently working on a more complete documentation which will then allow us to focus on version 0.3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pending a new transcription, the documentation is available on &lt;a href="https://maudbausier.com/biolab-kitchen-incubator-v0.2.html"&gt;maudbausier.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;...</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate></item><item><title>Now</title><link>https://domingoclub.com/now.html</link><description>&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;We are designing the next version of our incubator, taking into account the feedback received since our previous prototype. In short: a modular system for the electronics, an integrated screen and a parametric size for the cabinet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will be fabricating the new prototype this summer at &lt;a href="https://fablabbcn.org/"&gt;Fab Lab Barcelona&lt;/a&gt; as part of &lt;a href="https://foodshift2030.eu/"&gt;Food Shift&lt;/a&gt;'s Food Tech 3.0 programme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last month we moved to a new space, located in Poble Nou, Barcelona, Spain. We are in the process of setting up our local environment to accommodate people and workshops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last but not least, we are defining our business model and development plan to make this &lt;em&gt;Domingo Club&lt;/em&gt; a reality in the long term.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Sunny day at the office" src="office.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;...</description><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate></item><item><title>Water kefir</title><link>https://domingoclub.com/water-kefir.html</link><description>&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;h1 id="what-is-it"&gt;What is it?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Water kefir is an ancient fermented carbonated drink made from water kefir grains. Unlike ordinary kefir, which is made from milk, water kefir is made by combining sugar water with water kefir grains — a culture of bacteria and yeast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mixture ferments for ~36 hours, producing a probiotic drink rich in beneficial bacteria. This drink is refreshing, easy to enjoy and full of health benefits. We love it and drink it every day throughout the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="kefir-05.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="what-do-we-need-to-make-it"&gt;What do we need to make it?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id="ingredients-for-2-liters"&gt;Ingredients (for 2 liters)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;6 tablespoon of Water kefir grains&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 liters of water&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;​3 tablespoon of sugar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 dried fig&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Juice of half an organic lemon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="kefir-02.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="material"&gt;Material&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A glass jar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A wooden spoon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A plastic strainer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class="admonition notes"&gt;
&lt;p class="admonition-title"&gt;Why can't I use metal utensils?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exposure to metal can weaken the kefir grains. Indeed, kefir, being acidic, undergoes a modification of its structure in contact with aluminum, iron or copper. Stainless steel can be used without any problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h1 id="how-to-make-it"&gt;how to make it?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following process takes from 24 to 48h depending on your taste. The first fermentation produces the natural kefir, the second one brings the flavours and the fizz.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="first-fermentation"&gt;First fermentation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add kefir grains, water and sugar to the jar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stir to dissolve the sugar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add the lemon juice and the fig&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let ferment at room temperature for 24 hours&lt;/li&gt;...</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate></item><item><title>Soy tempeh</title><link>https://domingoclub.com/soy-tempeh.html</link><description>&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;h1 id="what-is-it"&gt;What is it?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tempeh is an Indonesian fermented food product originally made out of soy beans and a fungus called rhizopus. During the fermentation process, the spores of the fungus develop and its mycelium grows around the soybeans, breaking down their molecules. This process changes the properties of soybeans and makes them more digestible for our body, allowing us to absorb all the proteins available, and making tempeh as high in protein as meat. The taste evokes aromas of mushroom, nut and yeast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="tempeh-cooked-01.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="what-do-we-need-to-make-it"&gt;What do we need to make it?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id="ingredients-for-375-g-of-tempeh"&gt;Ingredients (for ~375 g of tempeh)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;250 g soybeans&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;​1⁄4 tablespoon of tempeh starter (rhizopus)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 tablespoon of vinegar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Organic soybeans, rhizopus &amp;amp; rice vinegar" src="process-01.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="material"&gt;Material&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Something to wrap the soybeans together, this can be plastic wrap, a zipper lock freezer bag or a mould&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An incubator, or a any other place that provides a constant temperature of about 30°C&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id="how-to-make-it"&gt;How to make it?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following process takes about 30 hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="remove-the-hulls"&gt;Remove the hulls&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Soak the soybeans in water overnight or cook for 20 minutes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Massage them in a basin to remove the hulls&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove the hulls from the water (by pouring the water from the basin, the hulls will come out first)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Repeat until there are almost no hulls left&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Cooking facilitates and accelerates the removal of the hulls" src="process-02.jpg"/&gt;
&lt;img alt="A little massage does the trick" src="process-...</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate></item><item><title>Sourdough starter</title><link>https://domingoclub.com/sourdough-starter.html</link><description>&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;h1 id="what-is-it"&gt;What is it?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sourdough "starter" is a mixture of flour and water that naturally collects yeast and bacteria. It is part of the bread making process called "pre-ferment".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making your own sourdough is very easy, the only ingredients you need are water, flour and a few days. The microorganisms will do the work for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you have it, making bread, banana bread and pancakes of all kinds will be absolutely delicious for your body and mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="admonition notes"&gt;
&lt;p class="admonition-title"&gt;What kind of flour?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is best to use a flour that contains at least 10% protein. The starter will be more active.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h1 id="how-to-make-it"&gt;How to make it?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following process takes about 7 days. It consists of mixing flour and water in a jar, waiting for it to start fermenting, then removing part of the mixture and adding water and flour in the same proportions to "feed" the starter, which will then become more and more active, day after day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="admonition notes"&gt;
&lt;p class="admonition-title"&gt;With the lid open or closed?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The jar should be covered to protect the sourdough but not completely closed to let it "breathe".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="day-1"&gt;Day 1&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mix 50 g water with 50 g flour in a large glass jar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep it at room temperature for approximately 24 hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="day-2"&gt;Day 2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add 100 g water and 100 g flour, mix well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Life is slowly settling in." src="01.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="day-3"&gt;Day 3+&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the starter starts to become active, keep ~100 g of the activated mixture and set the rest (~200 g) aside. Add 100 g of water and 100 g of flour. Mix well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Repeat the operation the following days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="admonition not...</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate></item><item><title>Terminal</title><link>https://domingoclub.com/terminal.html</link><description>&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;We use the terminal every day to perform repetitive tasks more quickly. Here are the commands we use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="images"&gt;Images&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id="resize-for-web"&gt;Resize for web&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resizes all images contained in the current folder with a certain extension &lt;code&gt;*.jpg&lt;/code&gt; to a certain width &lt;code&gt;-resize 1600&lt;/code&gt; with a certain quality &lt;code&gt;-quality 75&lt;/code&gt; in a folder named "web" &lt;code&gt;-path web&lt;/code&gt;. The folder must be created before running the command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;mogrify -resize 1600 -quality 75 -path web *.jpg
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;...</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate></item><item><title>Newsletter</title><link>https://domingoclub.com/newsletter.html</link><description>&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;Join the Domingo Club newsletter to receive our future updates. Don't worry, we don't send many newsletters, only when the announcement is significant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script&gt;
  (function (s, e, n, d, er) {
    s['Sender'] = er;
    s[er] = s[er] || function () {
      (s[er].q = s[er].q || []).push(arguments)
    }, s[er].l = 1 * new Date();
    var a = e.createElement(n),
        m = e.getElementsByTagName(n)[0];
    a.async = 1;
    a.src = d;
    m.parentNode.insertBefore(a, m)
  })(window, document, 'script', 'https://cdn.sender.net/accounts_resources/universal.js', 'sender');
  sender('a947da335f7959')
&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;div class="sender-form-field" data-sender-form-id="kmf543xgaqn7qbtckzw"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We respect your privacy and will never share your email address with third parties. Never ever.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;...</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate></item><item><title>About the Domingo Club</title><link>https://domingoclub.com/about.html</link><description>&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;Domingo Club is an initiative by &lt;a href="https://maudbausier.com/"&gt;Maud Bausier&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://antoine.studio/"&gt;Antoine Jaunard&lt;/a&gt;, a duo of Belgian designers with complementary forces, freshly settled in Barcelona, Spain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We make fermented &lt;a class="internal" href="food.html"&gt;food&lt;/a&gt;, open-source &lt;a class="internal" href="tools.html"&gt;tools&lt;/a&gt; and explore collaboration with natural processes to promote understanding, transparency, resilience and equity in our global food system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Big changes come from everyday habits, join us in the club and let's make our Sunday more impactful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="admonition notes"&gt;
&lt;p class="admonition-title"&gt;What's in the making?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Want to know what we are doing now? Visit our &lt;a class="internal" href="now.html"&gt;now&lt;/a&gt; page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Toni &amp;amp; Maudi, Barcelona, 2021" src="gif-duo.gif"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="philosophy"&gt;Philosophy&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fermented food provides delicious, protein-packed meals from natural ingredients that require little effort for maximum benefit. Power food is at our fingertips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We advocate open source tools (hardware and software) to allow others to understand, modify and repair the tools we produce. Together we will develop a proactive and hacktivist attitude.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe that partnering with living systems encourages us to move away from rapid, global manufacturing processes, helping us to be more conscious of our natural environment and its resources. Let's move towards a bio-based circular economy for a bright future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="focus"&gt;Focus&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the desire to encourage fermented food and food waste recycling, we design and develop an incubator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="admonition notes"&gt;
&lt;p class="admonition-title"&gt;What is an incubator?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An ...</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate></item><item><title>Links</title><link>https://domingoclub.com/links.html</link><description>&lt;html&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The prototype version of our Incubator Necklace &lt;a href="incubator-necklace.html"&gt;→ link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now ☼ &lt;a href="https://domingoclub.com/now.html"&gt;→ link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Our proposal for the Distributed Design Award 2021 &lt;a href="https://distributeddesign.eu/awards/entries/domingo-club-incubator/"&gt;→ link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The sources of our tempeh mould are now available on Wikifactory for the #FromOneToMany challenge &lt;a href="https://wikifactory.com/@domingoclub/tempeh-moulds"&gt;→ link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New recipe in our online documentation: Tempeh &lt;a href="soy-tempeh.html"&gt;→ link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="grains.png"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;...</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate></item></channel></rss>